

N A Z M U L A L A M

CONTACTS

2 CATHAIR DANANN TRALEE, CO KERRY V92 H5X5



083 311 4171



najm@protonmail.com



www.nalam.me



naz-mul



nalam

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL

Software Development

Developer Operations

User Interface Design

Leadership

TECHNICAL

 Java
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●
 ●</td

0000

ABOUT ME

Solutions-driven software engineer with a four-year track record of commended performance in web platforms and object-oriented programming. Well-versed in all phases of the software development lifecycle, with a strong working knowledge of design patterns, algorithms and data structures.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

FEXCO | JAN. 2016 - JUL. 2016 | KILLORGLIN, CO KERRY

- Develop micro-service based RESTful API for an intranet system with Spring Framework, Hibernate and Maven
- Implement front-end for the intranet with AngularJS and Bootstrap
- Build, package and support deployment releases with Jenkins CI and Amazon AWS
- Design, develop and unit test in accordance with established standards

LEAD SERVICE TECHNICIAN

PC SOLUTIONS | AUG. 2011 - SEP. 2013 | TRALEE, CO KERRY

- Designed, marketed and managed successful eBay shop
- Managed and mentored work placement students
- Effectively performed accurate diagnosis and repair of desktop,
 laptop and tablet computers





PROJECTS

DATAGRAM-FTP

Java / Design Patterns / Maven | DEC. 2016

A simple File Transfer Protocol client-server application using the Java Socket API

POI

Java / AngularJS / MongoDB | NOV. 2016

Point of Interest application using MEAN stack.

CompSys

C# / Oracle SQL / Software Engineering | APR. 2015 Computer repair management system.

EDUCATION

COMPUTING WITH SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY TRALEE | SEP. 2013 - MAY 2017

- Consistently achieved over 80% grade throughout the course
- Participated in IrlCPC in 2015 and 2016

JUNIOR AND LEAVING CERTIFICATE

CASTLEISLAND COMMUNITY COLLEGE | SEP. 2005 - JUN. 2010

VOLUNTEERING

CAMP LEADERS

THE FRESH AIR FUND | JUN. 2015 – AUG. 2015 | FISHKILL, NY Help expand the education and career options of NYC adolescents.

PROGRAMMING MENTOR

CODERDOJO | SEP. 2014 | TRALEE, CO KERRY

Mentor children the basics of coding and to assist them in their own self led learning by creating their own projects.

REFERENCES

Available on request